A Guide to the Correspondence of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1969-1974
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1969-1972
The Library of Virginia
29793
8.75 cubic feet (25 Boxes)
Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1978 Feb 1.
Historical Information
The Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth has evolved from early colonial times when there existed a Secretary of the Colony. Thomas Nelson held the position of the first Secretary of Virginia in 1776. Early Secretaries were elected by the public. An Act of the General Assembly in 1920 changed the election to a joint vote of the General Assembly. In a 1930 Act the duties of the Secretary were redefined with the Secretary of the Commonwealth serving as the ex officio secretary of the Governor, as custodian of many official State records, and as keeper of the Greater and Lesser Seals of the Commonwealth. The office of the Secretary has gradually acquired other functions, such as: service of out-of-state civil process; appointment and regulation of notaries public; and registration and oversight of lobbyists. The Office became a gubernational appointment subsequent to a 1958 Act of the Assembly. The Secretary of the Commonwealth is under the jurisdiction of the Governor's Office.
The Secretary is appointed by the Governor for a term of four years. Currently the Secretary of the Commonwealth is responsible for gubernatorial appointments, clemency and restoration of civil rights requests and extraditions. Additional activities include: serving as ex officio Secretary to the Governor; serving as keeper of the seals of the Commonwealth; compiling and publishing the annual Blue Book; commissioning and regulating notary publics, including the publication of a Notary Handbook and conduct of disciplinary hearings; promulgating the lobbying disclosure requirements, registration of lobbyists, and recording of lobbying reports; servicing the civil process of out-of-state defendants and other parties; and authenticating and certifying the records of the courts and of any state agency.
Scope and Content
Correspondence of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1969-1974, Cynthia Newman (1970-1974), during Governor Holton's Administration. The majority of the correspondence is related to appointments to boards and commissions, but may also include news clippings, reports, and other items.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in alphabetical order order.
Contents List
- Correspondence of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1969-1974.
  - Advisory Council on the Virginia Economy, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Accountancy, State Board, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Adjutant General, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Agriculture, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Agriculture, Commission on the Industry of, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Agricultural Foundation of Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Aide de Camp, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Air Pollution, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Airports Authority, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Commission to Study System of, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Alcoholism Advisory Council, State, 1969-1970. (Box 1)
  - Americas Committee, Virginia Partners of the, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Apprenticeship Council, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Art Commission, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Arts and Humanities Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Athletic Commission, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Atlantic Rural Exposition, Committee on the, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Audiology and Speech Pathology, Virginia Board for Examiners of, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Automated Data Processing Division, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Aviation Advisory Committee, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Aviation Transportation and Airport Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Barber Examiners, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Beef Cattle Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Bicentennial Commission, Virginia Independence, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Blue Cross Blue Shield, Study Commission on Organizations such as, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Breaks Interstate Parks Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Building Code Revies, Board of State, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Governor's Secretaries, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Chesapeake Bay Bridge-Tunnel Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 2)
  - Child Abuse, Task Force on, 1969-1970. (Box 3)
  - Children and Youth, Virginia Commission for, 1969-1970. (Box 3)
  - Children, White House Conference on, 1970. (Box 3)
  - City-County Relations, Study Commission on, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Code Commission, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Collection Agency Board, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Coastal Turnpike Authority, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - College Building Authority, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Community College Board, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Commercial Driver Training Schools, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Computer Advisory Committee, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Conduct for Public Officers and Employees, Commission Relating to Standards of, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Conservation and Economic Development, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Cook, Paul - Virginia State Travel Service, 1969-1970. (Box 4)
  - Consumer Credit Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Contractors, State Registration Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Corporation Commission, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Crime Commission, Virginia State, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Criminal Justice, Council of, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - County Courts Personnel, Committe to Fix Salaries of, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Deaf, Virginia Council for the, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Debt, Committee on Local, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Delmarva Advisory Council, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Dentistry, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Developmental Disabilities Planning and Advisory Council, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Drug Abuse Control Council, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Dulles and Washington Airports, Study Commission on, 1969-1970. (Box 5)
  - Eastern State Hospital Bicentennial Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Economy, Advisory Council on the Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Education Assistance Authority, State, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Education, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Education, State Council on Higher, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Educational Commission of the States, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Education, Board of Control for Southern Regional, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Education, Advisory Council on Vocational, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Elections, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Elizabeth River Tunnel Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Emergency Medical Services, Advisory Commission on, 1969-1970. (Box 6)
  - Employment for the Handicapped, Governor's Committee on, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Equal Employment Opportunities Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Energy Crisis Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Environmental Health Committee of the Council of State Governments, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Council on the Environment, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Escheators, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Executive Mansion, Citizen's Advisory Commission on Furnishing and Interpreting the, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Family, Physician Commisson on the Shortage of, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Forest Fire Protection Advisory Committee, Southeatrn Interstate, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Funeral Directors and Embalmers, Virginia Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Game and Inland Fisheries, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Gerontology Planning Section of the Commission on Aging, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Grant and Loan Commission, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Gunston Hall, 1969-1970. (Box 7)
  - Hairdressers, Board of Registered and Professional, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
  - Hampton Roads Sanitation District, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
  - Hampton Roads Area Toll Facility, Study Commission on Fincancing the, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
  - Health, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
  - Health Planning Council, Virginia Comprehensive, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
  - Health Education Committee for Health Professions and Occupations, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
  - Hearing Aid Dealers and Fitters, Virginia Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
  - Highway Commission, State, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
  - Highway Commission, State, 1969-1970. (Box 9)
  - Highway Safety Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 9)
  - Historic Landmarks Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 9)
  - Historic Landmarks Commission, Advisory Commission to the, 1969-1970. (Box 9)
  - Historic Archeology Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 9)
  - Hospital Board, State, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Hospital Advisory Council, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Housig, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Housing Development Authority, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Housing Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Human Resources, Division of, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Income Tax Conformity Statute, Study Commission on, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Industrial Building Authority, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Industrial Commission of Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Industrial Development Advisory Board, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Industrial Facilities Financing Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Insurance Board, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Interstate Cooperation Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - JJames Monroe Law Office Museum and Memorial Library - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Jamestown Foundation, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
  - Law Enforcement Officers Training Standards Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Law Enforcement Planning Council, State, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Legislation, Council on State, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Legislative Council, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Librarians, State Board for the Certification of, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Library Board, State, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Age of Majority to Eighteen Years, Study Commission - Commission to Study the Feasibility and Desirability of Lowering the Age of Majority to Eighteen Years, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Management, Commission on State Governmental, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Manpower Planning Council, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Marine Fisheries Commission, Atlantic States, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Marine Science, Virginia Institute of, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Medical College of Virginia - Commission to Study the Feasibility and Desirability of Transferring the NICU Property Adjacent to the MCV to the U.S. for Use by the Veterans Administration for a Hospital, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Medical Advisory Group, Regional, 1969-1970. (Box 11)
  - Medical Advisory - Board for the Division of Motor Vehicles, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Medical Examiners, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Medical Examiners, State Board of - Advisory Committee on Physical Therapy, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Medical Facilities in the Roanoke Area, Commission to Study the Utilization of, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Medical Facilities Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Medicare and Medicaid Advisory Committee, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Mental Health Research and Education Foundation, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Mental Health and Mental Retardation Advisory Board, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of Commissioner of, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Mental, Indigent and Geriatric Patients Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Metropolitan Area Transportation Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Military Affairs, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Miller School in Albemarle County - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Mine Examiners, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Minority Economic Development Advisory Committee, Governors, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Mount Vernon - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Milk Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Virginia - Board of Trustees, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Nurse Examiners, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Nurses, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 12)
  - Nursing Home Administrators, Board of Examiners for, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Nursing Training Advisory Council, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Optitians, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Optometry, Virginia State Board of Examiners in, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Outdoors Foundation, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Outdoor Recreation, Commission on, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Ohio River Basin Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Parimutuel Betting and Horse Racing, Study Commission on, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Pharmacy, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Pork Commission, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Port Authority, State, 1969-1970. (Box 13)
  - Ports - Plan for Refinancing Virginia Unified, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Potomac River Basin Compact, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Potomac River Fisheries Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Professional and Occupational Regulation, Dept. of, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Poultry Products Commission, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Probationa and Parole Board, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Property Tax Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Psychologist Examiners, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Public Employees, Commission to Study the Rights of, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Public School Authority, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Public Schools, Commission to Study State Assumption of Instructional Costs in the, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Purchases and Supply, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 14)
  - Pulaski County Developmental Authority, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Qualified Negroes, Appointment of, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Radiation Advisory Board, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Real Estate Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Reforestation Advisory Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Register Committee, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Revenue Resources and Economic Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Richmond-Petersburg Turnpike Authority, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Retirement System Board, Supplemental, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Sanitarian Examiners, State Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Safety and Health Codes Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - School Division Criteria Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Science Museum of Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 15)
  - Securities, Issuance and Sale, Commission on, 1969-1970. (Box 16)
  - Seed Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 16)
  - Seed Potato Commission, State, 1969-1970. (Box 16)
  - Selective Service Program, 1969-1970. (Box 16)
  - Social Workers, Board of Registration of, 1969-1970. (Box 16)
  - Southern Growth Policies Board, 1969-1970. (Box 16)
  - Southern Interstate Nuclear Board, 1969-1970. (Box 16)
  - Soybean Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 16)
  - State Employees, Commission to Study Legislative Compensation and Compensation of Certain, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - State Police, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Status of Women, Virginia Commission on the, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Sweet Potato Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Telecommunications Council, Virginia Public, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Tobacco Commission, Virginia Bright Flue-Cured, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Tobacco Commission, Virginia Dark-Fired, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Tobacco, Commission to Study Matters related to, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Tobacco-Textile Museum, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Travel Advisory Committee, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Truck and Ornamentals Research Station, Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Urban Assistance Incentive Fund, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Veterans Affairs, Commission on, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Veterinary Examiners, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Veterinary Medicine, School of, Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Visually Handicapped, Commission for the, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - Vocational Rehabilitation, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 17)
  - War Veterans Claims, Division of, 1969-1970. (Box 18)
  - Water Control Board, State, 1969-1970. (Box 18)
  - Water and Wastewater Works Operators, Certification Board for, 1969-1970. (Box 18)
  - Welfare and Institutions, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 18)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind, 1969-1970. (Box 18)
  - Virginia's Wetland Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 18)
  - Youth Advisory Council, Governor's, 1969-1970. (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1970. (Box 18)
  - College and University Boards - General, 1969-1970. (Box 19)
  - George Mason University - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 19)
  - Longwood College - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 19)
  - Madison College - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 19)
  - Mary Washington College - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 19)
  - Norfolk State College - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 19)
  - Old Dominion University - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 19)
  - Radford College - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 19)
  - University of Virginia - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 20)
  - University of Virginia - Student Council Report, 1970. (Box 20)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 20)
  - Virginia Military Institute - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 20)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 20)
  - Virginia State University - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 20)
  - William and Mary, College of - Board of Visitors, 1969-1970. (Box 20)
  - Corrections, Board of, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Arizona, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - California, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Florida, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Hawaii, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Idaho, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Iowa, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Kansas, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Louisiana, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Massachusetts, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Maryland, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Michigan, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Mississippi, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Missouri, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Montana, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Nebraska, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - Nevada, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - New Hampshire, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - New Jersey, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - New Mexico, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - New York, 1969-1970. (Box 21)
  - Corrections, Board of - North Carolina, 1969-1970. (Box 22)
  - Corrections, Board of - North Dakota, 1969-1970. (Box 22)
  - Corrections, Board of - Oregon, 1969-1970. (Box 22)
  - Corrections, Board of - Pennsylvania, 1969-1970. (Box 22)
  - Corrections, Board of - South Carolina, 1969-1970. (Box 22)
  - Corrections, Board of - South Dakota, 1969-1970. (Box 22)
  - Corrections, Board of - Vermont, 1969-1970. (Box 22)
  - Corrections, Board of - Virginia, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Corrections, Board of - Washington State, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Corrections, Board of - Washington, DC, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Corrections, Board of - Wisconsin, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Corrections, Board of - Wyoming, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Commissioner of Adminstration, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Executive Assistant, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Budget, Division of - Director, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Budget, Division of - Assistant Director, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Treasury, Dept. of the - Director, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Civil Defense Coordinator, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Civil Defense Coordinator - Briefing Guide, 1970. (Box 23)
  - Community Colleges, Dept. of - Director, 1969-1970. (Box 23)
  - Community Colleges - Florida, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Community Colleges - North Carolina, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Comptroller, State, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Conservation and Economic Development, Dept. of - Director, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Corporation Commission, State, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Data Processing, Division of Automated - Director, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Economic Opportunity, Offic of - Coordinator, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Electoral Board, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Employment Commission - Commissioner, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Engineering and Buildings, Division of - Director, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Federal State Relations, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Game and Inland Fisheries, Dept. of - Director, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Governor's Office - Staff, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Health Dept., 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Highway Safety Division, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Human Resources Division, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Industrial Development, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Intern Committee, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Labor Dept. - Commissioner, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Law Enforcement Planning Council, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Marine Resources - Commissioner, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Appointees - Resumes, 1969-1970. (Box 25)